unitycharterschool.org 2019-12-12

# Privacy Policy - Unity Charter School

Your privacy is very important to us. At Unity Charter School we have a few fundamental principles that we follow:

  * We don’t ask you for personal information unless we truly need it.
  * We don’t share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights.
  * We don’t store personal information on our servers unless required for the on-going operation of our site.

Unity Charter School’s policy is to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our website.

**Website Visitors**

Like most website operators, Unity Charter School collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Unity Charter School’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Unity’s visitors use its website. From time to time,Unity Charter School may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

Unity Charter School also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments on our blogs. Unity Charter School only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below, except that blog commenter IP addresses are visible and disclosed to the administrators of the blog where the comment was left.

**Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information**

Certain visitors toUnity Charter School’s websites choose to interact withUnity Charter School in ways that requireUnity Charter School to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information thatUnity Charter School gathers depends on the nature of the interaction.Unity Charter School does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

**Aggregated Statistics**

Unity Charter School may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. For instance,Unity Charter School may monitor the most popular pages on the list25.com site or use spam screened by the Akismet service to help identify spam.Unity Charter School may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However,Unity Charter School does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

**Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information**

Unity Charter School discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it onUnity Charter School’s behalf or to provide services available atUnity Charter School’s website, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Unity Charter School’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them.Unity Charter School will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Unity Charter School discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when Unity Charter School believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Unity Charter School, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of an Unity Charter School website and have supplied your email address, Unity Charter School may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Unity Charter School and our products. We primarily use our various product blogs to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Unity Charter School takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

**Cookies**

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Unity Charter School uses cookies to help Unity Charter School identify and track visitors, their usage of Unity Charter School website, and their website access preferences. Unity Charter School visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Unity Charter School’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of Unity Charter School’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

**Business Transfers**

If Unity Charter School, or substantially all of its assets were acquired, or in the unlikely event that Unity Charter School goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of Unity Charter School may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.

**Ads**

Ads appearing on any of our websites may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Unity Charter School and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

**Comments**

Comments and other content submitted to Akismet anti-spam service are not saved on our servers unless they were marked as false positives, in which case we store them long enough to use them to improve the service to avoid future false positives.

**Privacy Policy Changes**

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Unity Charter School may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Unity Charter School’s sole discretion. Unity Charter School encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

Unity is a truly special place. We believe that learning spans beyond textbooks, and that education is most valuable when it prepares students to face the real-world challenges of today and tomorrow. At Unity, we foster a culture of creativity, innovation and change that inspires a future generation of thinkers and doers, just as they inspire us.

Our tuition-free public elementary school (K-8) provides a holistic, student-centered learning experience, where academic excellence is infused with sustainability education and stewardship. Through a dynamic classroom approach, we invite students to explore and assess real-life challenges in order to acquire a deeper knowledge of the world in which we live. Our passionate staff develops 21st century leaders through exciting and engaging learning activities and actions.

Our unique field-based, interdisciplinary and service-oriented learning approach encourages students to thrive beyond the classroom walls. We’re proud to produce graduates that are engaged global citizens, inspired to tackle complicated issues and make a difference. We also take great pride in being named the only charter school in New Jersey We also take great pride in being named the only charter school in New Jersey We also take great pride in being named the only charter school in New Jersey—and one of only three schools in the nation—to have received the Eco-School’s USA Green Flag for Exceptional Green Achievement three times.

We are fun, inventive and artistic. We are enthusiastic, inspired and collaborative. We welcome a talented, diverse student population into the Unity family, where we provide a unique learning environment that champions acceptance, celebrates uniqueness, and is deeply rooted in our beliefs.
